

Fabio J. Fehr

Research assistant at Idiap, PhD candidate at EPFL

25/05/1996, Swiss & South African

fabio.fehr@idiap.ch

in LinkedIn Profile

Research Profile

About me

I advocate for leadership by example. I believe that the values: honesty, humility and kindness are the ultimate form of optimisation – free to give and invaluable to receive. I am passionate and tenacious in my research and think that the progress direction is more important than the progress magnitude. My happiest state: rigorous mental stimulation, relaxing social interaction and regular outdoor exercise. For leisure, I enjoy spending time in nature: sunshine, sea and snowy mountains.

Interests



Languages

English

French

Afrikaans

German

Education

Tertiary: Postgraduate

2021 – 2024 **Doctor of Philosophy: Electrical Engineering**Research in machine learning and natural language processing.

PhD Research

EPFL

EPFL

EPFL

EPFL

Combining Variational Bayesian nonparametric methods with deep

attention-based models for representation learning.

2019 – 2020 Masters: Advanced Analytics
Statistics specialisation and awarded SASA_NPE full burgary

Statistics specialisation and awarded SASA-NRF full bursary. **Masters Thesis**

A comprehensive comparison study of Gaussian processes and variational autoencoders for statistical shape modelling of 3D meshes.

UCT

Tertiary: Undergraduate

2015 – 2018 Bachelors of Business Science: Analytics

Commerce degree with a specialisation in mathematics & statistics. **Honours Thesis (Distinction)**UCT

Statistical machine learning techniques for classifying news articles. Presented at South African Statistical Association (SASA) 2019.

Experience

2021-2024	Research Assistant	Idiap
	Natural Language Processing and Deep Learning research	arch.
2018	Intern Machine Learning Engineer	DataProphet
	Transfer learning for financial time-series data.	
2017 - 2018	Intern Data Scientist	Eighty20
	Data visualisation dashboard for the water crisis in Cape To	

Teaching

2021-2024	Teaching Assistant	EPFL
	Machine learning, Deep learning and NLP courses at EPFL.	
2019-2024	Subject Matter Expert & Engagement Tutor	2U
	Business Analytics (UCT), Machine Learning (LSE).	
2017 – 2020	Head Tutor: Statistics	UCT
	Managing, coordination, tutoring and assistant lecturing.	

Publications

PhD Research

2023	Nonparametric Variational Regularisation of Pretrained	ArXiv 2023
2023	Transformers Learning to Abstract with Nonparametric Variational	EMNLP 2023
2022	Information Bottleneck A VAE for Transformers with Nonparametric Variational	ICLR 2023
	Information Bottleneck	

Research collaborations

2022 HyperMixer: An MLP-based Low Cost Alternative to ACL 2023
Transformers

Mr. Allan Clark - allan.clark@uct.ac.za

References

PhD supervisorIdiapDr. James Henderson - james.henderson@idiap.chUCTMSc supervisorsUCTProf. Tinashe Mutsvangwa - tinashe.mutsvangwa@uct.ac.za